
This construction is inspired by the idea of ... in .... 

As demonstrated heuristically and numerically by ... et al., ... algorithms can effectively solve the reconstruction problem.

Sparse recovery has drawn much attention in the signal processing and general systems community recently, 
but its applications in networks are still limited.
Introducing sparse recovery to network applications brings new challenges.

Recovering a sparse signal from an undersampled set of random linear measurements is the main problem of interest in compressed sensing.

The focus is on signals with sparse non-zero values that are contaminated by Gaussian measurement noise. 



%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%
命名

termed
coined
referred to as




动词大全
address
adopt
alleviate
analyse
claim
compare 
concern
conduct
conclude
consider
demostrate
describe
derive
develop
devise
discover
emphasize
employ
enlighten
envision
enhance
exhibit
examine
explore
exploit
expose
formulate
give
guarantee
generalize
highlight
illustrate
improve
inspire
introduce 
investigate
obtained
outline
perform
predict
preserve
prevent
produce
propose
prove
raise
review
reflect
show
study
suggest
summarize 
survey
tend to
tackle the challenge
use
validate


placing particular emphasis on the initialization of NMF
propose using ... to produce ... for ...

%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%
形容词
versatile
miscellaneous
pervasive
all-round
novel
intrinsic
exhaustively
surprising
intuitive
representative
inefficient
simplicity
scalability
fairly good
flexibility
stability
viability
ubiquity


computationally tractable
advisable
impractical
favorable
significant
remarkable
acceptable
provalble
comparable
reliable  /  high reliability
substantial
alleviate
significantly



%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%
习惯用语


top panel 上图
lower panel


we address an important issue of ... for ...
... does not actually meet this requirement because ...
to this end
the core is to ...
Nevertheless, the issue of ...  has not been considered yet in the literature.
Actually,
this paper investigates
simulation results have indicated the effectiveness of our scheme.
it is worth noting that
our goal is to develop ...


xxx proposed in [15] is adapted to the CS problem.


address the theoretical limitations in


a broad spectrum of ...
... hold the promise to enable ....
...still fall short of ...
is a main comparative advantage of

新方法处理老问题
The double inversion recovery (DIR) imaging technique has various applications
such as black blood magnetic resonance imaging and gray/white matter imaging.
Recent clinical studies show the promise of DIR for high resolution three dimensional (3D) gray matter imaging.
One drawback in this case however is the long data acquisition time needed
to obtain the fully sampled 3D spatial frequency domain (k-space) data.
In this paper, we propose a method to solve this problem using the compressed sensing (CS) algorithm with contourlet transform.
The contourlet transform is an effective sparsifying transform especially for images with smooth contours.
Therefore, we applied this algorithm to undersampled DIR images and compared
with a CS algorithm using wavelet transform by evaluating the reconstruction
performance of each algorithm for undersampled k-space data.
The results show that the proposed CS algorithm achieves a more accurate reconstruction
in terms of the mean structural similarity index and root mean square error than the CS algorithm using wavelet transform.


结论
We have introduced .... which can be used to alleviate the problem of .....
Our proposed algorithm improves the reconstruction accuracy (in terms of MSSIM index and RMS error) compared to ....
We have shown that the proposed algorithm can be an effective method for ....


提出什么算法, 比以前的好在哪
we obtain new measurement matrix constructions and algorithms for signal recovery which, 
compared to previous algorithms, are superior in either the number of measurements or computational efficiency of decoders.

随着xxx的发展
With the rise in high-speed data transmission and the exponential increase in data storage, 
it is imperative that we develop effective data compression techniques, 
techniques which accomodate both the volume and speed of data streams.




Estimating the parameter of ....distribution is an interesting question 
since this distribution arises in many situations of applied probability.



实验结果验证了本文方法
Through extensive experimentation with synthetic data 
we show that this technique outperforms various other state-of-the-art techniques in resolving fiber crossings.

Finally, we demonstrate the effectiveness of this method using real DW-MRI data from ratbrain and optic chiasm.


引言说别人方法的缺点
Though this model has been effective in modeling ...., 
it has the major limitation that it cannot cope with ....

Though these methods are capable of handling more complex ...., 
they do not necessarily yield ....

These methods suffer from the two major problems.

贡献
The seminal contribution of this work was the ....

To overcome this limitation of .... , .... was proposed by [11].



实验

It can be noted in Fig....  that the proposed method performs significantly better than .... especially in the higher noise cases. 
Furthermore, the performance of the proposed model is generally similar to that of ...., especially in the typical case of ....

In addition to the quantitative error measurements,

To quantitatively compare the performance of our method with other methods, ....

These two experiments validate the accuracy of our model in .... and demonstrate its robustness in....

We further find that .... compares favourably to ...., particularly for small sample sizes



Our work draws inspiration from the works of XXX et
al. [27] and Subbarao and Meer [24], where the Euclidean
MS formulation was extended to two particular analytic
manifolds, Grassmann manifolds and Lie groups, and named
as nonlinear MS. The basic idea behind the nonlinear MS


Our data set is provided to us 【with the courtesy of 】xx[1]

We also present detailed experimental comparisons of the proposed algorithms

Extensive experimental results are provided on benchmark text and gene-expression data sets
to show the efficacy of the proposed algorithms for high-dimensional,


be akin to 
is a analog of


take ... into account
it make little sense to speak

MATLAB like notation
the platform used was a 2.0GHz pentium IV with 1024MB RAM rinning windows. codes were written in MATLAB 7.6.

underlying principal 原理


schematic diagram　示意图
flowchart 流程图
acronym 首字母缩略词
scenario
paradigms
provides a fresh opportunity for 
more details can be found in 
Good surveys covering the topic may be found in
some appealing aspects
xxx is appealing for.... due to... 





Without losing generality,

For more information about ICA, you may want to refer to a survey [7].
see [10] for a beautiful introduction.


只能列举部分文献，研究仍旧是个开放问题
We can hardly be exhaustive, and the references contained therein as a partial list of related work. It still an open issue for research community to deterministic initialization strategies.




The last decade has witnessed great advancement in nearly all areas in computer
vision and pattern recognition.

Zhu [145] have develops a deep insight into
different streams of the learning models, and divides them into four basic
categories based on their semantic structures: descriptive models, variants of
descriptive models, generative models and discriminative models.

are done simultaneously with the image segmentation through the combination
of bottom-up descriptive models and top-down generative models using

Similarity measure is crucial for image retrieval. Earth Mover's Distance (EMD), which is not only computation exhausted, but also relies on efficient ground distance, is an efficient distance measure. Modeling images by Lloyd clustering, choosing clustering distortions as ground distance, we propose two similarity measures to approximate EMD. And experiment results demonstrate the effectiveness of our proposed methods. With similar performance compared with EMD, they not only further reduce the computation complexity, but also aren’t sensitive to the ground distance.

effectiveness robustness and efficiency
effective robust efficient 

competitive/similar/superior performance as ....
investigate the performance of ...


... has received much attention in ...


%compare our proposed approaches with ... for image retrieval on Corel image dataset, Experimental results show that
%... achieves better retrieval precision while being much more efficient.

% better retrieval performance than state-of-art method

% experimented results show that our methods are effective and demostrate muck higher performance in comparison to LPP LDE

% extensive experiments have been designed and conducted to compare our method to the state-of-art techniques
% the results show the superior performance of SDP

% has the limitation of singularity problem[undersampled], to overcome this apply PCA+LDA

reduced complexity CBIR using .....

present a low complexity approach for ..

... serve as generative image models

yield a better representation than...

experiments performed on ... image database support this hypothesis, and retrieval based on this method compares well with previous work.



expressiveness

less sensitive to noisy 

outperform other distance measure in terms of both retrieval accuracy and retrieval efficiency.





%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%

Simulation results on several data sets are presented to demonstrate the 
efficacy of the proposed method over several other reported BSS methods.


%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%


%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%


%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%
Pred. --    Pos.(+)    Neg.(-)

Pos.(+)    P(+|+)TP   P(-|+)FN   P(+)

Neg.(-)    P(+|-)FP   P(-|-)TN   P(-)

 |
Act.

“true positive” rate (TP), “false positive” rate (FP)
“true negative” rate (TN), “false negative” rate (FN)

Cost Curve [ C(+|-) = C(-|+) ]

X: p(+) [x=0, y=FP; x=1, y=FN=1-TP]

Y: Error Rate = (FN - FP) * p(+) + FP

一般情况[ C(+|-) ~= C(-|+) ]
Y: normalized expected cost  X: PC(+)

E[Cost] = FN * p(+) * C(-|+) + FP * p(-) * C(+|-) [p(-) = 1 - p(+)]

Norm(E[Cost]) = E[Cost] / p(+) * C(-|+) +  p(-) * C(+|-) [FP=FN=1]

X: PC: probability times cost
PC(a) = p(a) * C(~a|a) / p(+) * C(-|+) + p(-) * C(+|-)
[a is a class, either + or - ]

PC(-) = 1 - PC(+) 当PC(+) = p(+)
PC(+) = 0 当 p(+) = 0 or C(-|+) = 0
PC(+) = 1 当 p(-) = 0 or C(+|-) = 0

Norm(E[Cost]) = (FN - FP) * PC(+) + FP
[ x=0, y=FP; x=1, y=FN ]

适用于签名鉴别??  样本很小的!! 2:2:20/20= [0.1-1]



%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%

先从EEG(electroencephalogram) 脑动电流图  EMG(Electromyogram) 肌动电流图 做起

NTD(Nonnegative Tucker Decomposition) 这样就有张量分解方法

人体运动分析human movement analysis
kinematics

L. Wang and X. Geng (eds), Behavioural Biometrics for Human Identification: 
Intelligent Application, IGI Global, 2009.

L. Wang, L. Cheng and G. Y. Zhao (eds),  Machine Learning for Human Motion Analysis: 
Theory and Practice, IGI Global, 2009. 

D. Schonfeld, C. F. Shan, D. C. Tao, and L. Wang (eds), Video Mining, Springer, 2009 


http://www.cs.mu.oz.au/~lwwang/index_files/book_behavior.html


曲线匹配方法研究
DTW是EMD的一种约束解[时序约束], 连续DTW, FastDTW, ER^2  

结合生成模型delt-lognormal 和判别模型NMF
怎么结合????

基于数据分解的在线手写签名鉴别/认证研究
基于判别模型的在线手写签名鉴别/认证研究
functional approach
parametric approach


Dynamic signature verification using NMF



Decomposition methods for On-line Handwritting Signature Verification

Biometric authentication 身份验证/认证
分physiological/physical biometrics 生理生物特征识别 
behaviorial biometrics 行为生物特征识别

Biometric handwritting signature recognition  识别
verification 确认 鉴别/验证 1:1
Identification  认证   1:n

Biometrics: the study of methods for uniquely recognizing humans based upon 
one or more intrinsic physical or behavioral traits

Biometrics are used to identify the input sample when compared to a template, 
used in cases to identify specific people by certain characteristics


数据获取 acquisition [以前很少研究是因为签名采集困难]
- 手写板 Window Tablet Application

预处理 preprocessing
- 起笔处理、虚假抬笔剔除、平滑、归一化
Gaussian filter
rotation
normalization


global/local feature
结构特征[形状/几何特征] static shape information 也是offline识别的唯一信息
the shape is only available information in offline signatures
 笔画分布、宽高比 X方向投影 抬笔/落笔[a pen up or down indicator, 也是status动态信息吧]


时序特征 
dynamic feature/information makes the signature more unique and more difficult to forge
 Each signature containing xxx for each point on the signature trajectory

 coordinate information坐标信息 X-Y coordinate of the pen tip
 pressure压力
 频率、velocity速度 acceleration加速度 
 pen orientation 
 azimuth angle 方位角 0°-360°
 inclination/ altitude angle 倾斜角 30°-90°

---[Rioja2004]
Initial and final point signature
Writing order
Pressure change in axis X and Y
Speed change in axis X and Y
Region with high pressure in the signature
Region with high and low speed in axis X and Y

a) Initial and final points
b) Writing order
c) Writing speed in X and Y axis
d) Pen pressure
e) High pressure region
f) High and low speed region in X and Y axis




real stroke virtual stroke 实笔 虚笔


NMF分解的不确定性 需要加入sparse约束


- Decomposition methods for unsupervised learning EEG
  Morup, Morten  morten.morup@gmail.com mm@imm.dtu.dk
- 协作 synergy  EMG
- NMF/NTF/NTD kim

比较算法[快速人体运动理论-基元协作]
- delta-lognormal model 生成模型 --> 参数估计

Bechmark Database 
- SVC2004
- HIT_SignatureDB
- SUSIG

Multibiometric Fusion
- 多特征 结构特征/时序特征
- 离线特征

分类器设计 matching 距离? similarity
GM高斯 Lloyd失真 EMD 

curve matching 曲线匹配 
直接用EMD距离?
与 语音识别 时序分析 计算几何 形状匹配 相同

genuine/forgery signature
skilled forgerise/informed forgeries
random forgeries 
genuine impostors 真的伪造者
random forgery 
simple forgery 
expert forgery


Verification protocols:
------------------------
enrollment/training 注册登记 训练 reference signature
matching/testing 匹配 测试 test signature

[reference set] used for enrolling users to a system
[validation set] tuning system-specific parameters
[test set] testing the performance
上述set不能重合 [采用交叉验证]

Summary of the protocols
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Protocol                                Reference  Genuine test           Forgery test
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Visual subcorpus
Single-session                          VS1[1-5]   VS1[6-10]                VSF + VHSF 
                                        VS2[1-5]   VS2[6-10]                VSF + VHSF
Across-session                          VS1[1-5]   VS2[1-10]                VSF + VHSF
                                        VS2[1-5]   VS1[1-10]                VSF + VHSF
Base (=mixed session)                   VS1[1-5]   VS1[6-10] + VS2[1-10]    VSF + VHSF
Skilled forgery                         VS1[1-5]   VS1[6-10] + VS2[1-10]    VSF
Highly skilled forgery                  VS1[1-5]   VS1[6-10] + VS2[1-10]    VHSF
Random forgery                          VS1[1-5]   VS1[6-10] + VS2[1-10]    Others’ genuine signatures

Blind subcorpus
Base (=single-session/skilled forgery)  BS1[1-5]   BS1[6-8/10]              BSF
Random forgery                          BS1[1-5]   BS1[6-8/10]              Others’ genuine signatures

Whole database
Device independent                      VS1[1-5]   BS1[1-8/10]              BSF
                                        BS1[1-5]   VS1[1-10] + VS2[1-10]    VSF + VHSF
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------



performance evaluation
FRR: false rejection rates 误拒率 拒识率 错误拒绝率
FAR: false acceptance rates 误纳率 误识率 错误接受率
EER: equal error rates 等误差率/等错误率 等错率 相等错误率 相对错误率
ROC: receiver operating characteristic curve  X轴[FRR]-Y轴[FAR]
怎么算 FRR FAR 平均
ROC又是怎么画的? 采用不同的similarity scores 得到不同FRR FAR

after the dissimilarity value is computed, a decision regarding whether the signature is authentic or a forgery must be made.
怎么判断真假签名?

computed to a threshold 

impostor/professional imitator

benchmark database/result

签名的人称 contributor / each subject
分阶段采集数据 session

handwritten signature databases are highly language dependent 语言相关的

GMM & VQ 还是log-normal分解笔划之后用?

速度域用小波 郑建斌

中西签名比较 笔划多少 速度曲线 EER

parzen Window 改用 meanshift

DTW 曲线匹配: 连续DTW 近似算法 跟EMD区别? [没有考虑权重, 按先后顺序匹配]

NMF笔划分解 后用GMM失真度量距离 采用Alisher三维向量 再降维PCA
NTF/NTD怎么用?


笔划方法与语言相关[Lei2004 ER^2]
Segmentation-based methods [7] are dependent on languages
to a large degree, since the words of some languages
are complex with a lot of possible segments and the segments
may be not consistent.



[hansheng Lei ph.d]

@PHDTHESIS{phd05,
  AUTHOR =       {Hansheng Lei},
  TITLE =        {Sequential Pattern Classification Without Explicit Feature Extraction},
  SCHOOL =       {State University of New York at Buffalo},
  YEAR =         {2005},
}

one approach to avoidding explicit feature selection is to use a (dis)similarity 
representation instead of a feature vector representation.
用相似度量/距离取代 显式特征选取

Paucity of training samples can render the traditional training methods ineffective as
in the case of on-line signatures where the number of training samples is rarely 
greater than 10. 
小样本 训练样本太少

featureless classification/learning
1. feature based
2. (dis)similarity  based


as one of the biometric authentication methods, signature has been widely accepted,
because it is more user-friendly than fingerprint, iris, retina and face.
用户友好 广被采用

there are two challenge issues in on-line signature verification:
1. intra-personal variation
2. paucity of training samples

即一致性问题 consistency

这么做到 ER^2 is a language-independent measure

curve matching is a promising and general approach, because curve matching is language-independent.

segmentation-based methods are dependent on languages to a large degree.
[efficient retrieval of similar time sequences using DFT]


 
there is an unsubstantiated claim in on-line signature verification community that the
curve of the signature should be re-sampled with uniform arc-length.
没必要重采样

the decision boundary for one-category classification is a closed hyper-plane.
[only one cluster of genuine signatures, while forgeries have no clustering characteristic 
because they have no reason to be close to each other]
属于单类模式识别问题, 决策边界为闭合超平面 这样有必要非线性降维?


时序数据挖掘 time sequence data mining

线性EMD NMF分解后正好是长度不一, 所占长度算权值

curve matching 连续DTW



NMF 用V_x V_y V_p 三个速度特征

看中文DTW 代码

IJBM 或 ER^2 结合Alisher方法 FastDTW替代DTW 怎么改进? 三个特征 VQ PCA? Fusion[特征, 匹配]

预处理[1. gaussian filter 2. rotation 3. normalization ]

%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%
以前不知道NMF的应用方法, 时间序列
肌肉协作论文看起


这几天在看那三分资料, 总的来说, 现在只有个概念框架, 就写下现在的认识, 
想从现有基础再看相关论文, 以后的理解可能会有差异. 今后工作的重点概况起来
就从两个方面: 基元协作和核学习, 理解仿生运动感知与控制, 而学习的难点在于步态/签名
等身份识别中感知数据的动态性. 即怎么对时序感知数据的建模(时空相关性的解决).
我计划从nmf在签名中的应用开始, 先看快速人体运动理论, 肌肉协作. 签名笔划分解的其他方法
(plamondon 及pami综述) kernel学习 kernel method for pattern analysis
learning with kernel  基于张量的学习方法 支持张量机 非负张量分解

现在要了解的
感知数据的获取及其物理涵义
delta lognormal model 和NMF 在手写签名的笔划分解中可以看作时序数据的聚类
按照快速人体运动理论, 单笔笔划可以看作是一个gaussian, 连续笔划即为具有时间差异的
高斯混合, delta lognormal model是GMM的推广生成模型, 通过参数估计求解.
而NMF是判别模型, 根据样本数据找出单笔笔划, 由于delta lognormal model 参数估计比较
复杂, 要估计的参数多, 而且处理具有多峰的数据存在过拟合. NMF可能避免这个问题

识别器的设计问题, 可以用GMM的失真/KL散度作为度量? 参考图像检索的做法
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%


%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%





%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%
% 引言
%
%
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%

a building block for xxxx



we may assume without loss of generality that U is already a pullback so that σ(U) = In.
不失一般性

Needless to say, the limit point depends on the starting value U(0).
不用说 明显

we follow the notation introduced in Ref. [3],

NMF is akin to xxx 
与... 类似/相同

xxx envisioned by 作者


Details of its mathematical theory can be found in [25]. The method
originally proposed in [25] computes xxx

we have developed a ... for ...
 

In this study, xxx is [recast as] the problem of xxx

This approach [leads to a convenient way] of computing the proximity
map which, in contrast to most existing algorithms where only an approximate map is used, 


This paper [sets up] a theoretical framework, [outlines] a numerical algorithm, 
and [suggests] an effective implementation. Testing results strongly evidence
that this approach obtains a better low rank nonnegative matrix approximation in fewer steps than
conventional methods.

The problem of nonnegative matrix factorization (NMF) [arises in] a large variety 
of disciplines in sciences and engineering. Its wide range of important
applications such as text mining, ..., and so on has attracted considerable research efforts.

Many different kinds of NMF techniques [have been proposed] in the literature, notably the
popular Lee and Seung iterative update algorithm [17, 18]. Successful applications
to various models with nonnegative data values are abounding. 

We can hardly be exhaustive by suggesting [6-24], 
and the references contained therein as a partial list of interesting work. 
The review article [27] contains many other more recent applications and references.
列举参考文献

A good survey of other interesting NMF applications can be found
in [27, section 6.2].



.. have devoted to ...


...are at the root of....

a core problem for image database and digital libraries is that CBIR, where images specified by a
query must be retrieved from a large image database. 


with the ever increasing amounts of  machine generated imagery, the need has never been greater for efficient and effective systems to manage visual data and understand its content.

todays abudance fo storage coupled with digital technologies

deal with tremendous quantities of images 

... is too complex for usage in interactive multimedia database scenarios.


there has been substantial progress,  especially in CBIR where color images are retrieved from multimedia database using three main concepts: feature extraction model, which maps each image to a set of attributes, the so-called features. secondly, a distance measure between these features which reflects the underlying similarity model. and finally, storage and retrieval methods for large image databade.
several models have been proposed for feature extraction procsee. 

直方图histogram approach, which maps each image to a vector of attributes encoding 



we follow the "query-by-example" model, where the user supplies an image and the system returns 
the best matching imagesin the database.

image are first represented by feature vector. 

the most important discriminating feature is color 

color distribution in an image can be modeled by a histogram of the intensities.

GMVQ is performed on image blocks instead of single pixels, some spatial information is implicitly included.


we investigate the properties of ...




In this paper, a novel approach of
learning the similarity measure using feature subspaces analysis (FSA) is proposed for
content-based image retrieval. This approach solves the similarity measure-learning problem by
FSA on training samples, which improves generalization capacity and reserves robustness
furthest simultaneously. Experiments on a large database of 13,897 heterogeneous images
demonstrated a remarkable improvement of retrieval precision.

This scheme achieves both good
generalization performance and stable retrieval precision.

The number of training samples is usually less than the
dimensionality of features, and so these methods have to offer singular or diagonal matrix as similarity
measure, which is a local minimum solution under some constraints and may be far away from the
really optimal solution.

This paper is organized as follow.
Section 2 reviews the related work. In section 3 the proposed approach is described in detail.
Experimental results are shown and compared to existing methods in Section 4. Final discussions
and conclusions are given in Section 5.

The dataset comprises 13,897 heterogeneous images selected from the Corel image collection.
These images have been labeled into 139 categories and each category contains about 100 images.
Images from the same category are considered relevant. 500 images are randomly selected from
the dataset as the initial queries and the average performance is reported


with the development of ... and availability of ....

the size of ... is increasingly rapidly

.. have gained popularity in ...

... are required by users from various domains, including .....

for this purpose, ... have been developed 

to overcome the disadvantages of ... , ... was introduced in .... 1990's

.... is the basis of ...

 ... is modeled with a mixture of gaussians

the motivation for .. derives from a formula for 

a key ingredient of designing successful ... systems is how to effectively ..

one of the most challenging proplems for .. is find ...

Traditional approaches often assume that ...

our research indicates this assumption is inappriate in many cases.


%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%
% 实验
%
%
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%


the image database are already relatively small, but still larger than in need for a thumbnail.

LUV color space where the Eucldiean distance between colors closely approximates their perceptual distance.


compare our work with ...

.. used on the average 1/2 of the time of ....

it can be seen from figure.. that although ...  offers a lower complexity retrieval solution than ..., the precision is not affected, in fact the ... approach performs marginally better than ....

From figure....  it can be seen that ... give an overall modest improvement in performance.

... as can be seen from figure....

figure... shows .....

significantly lower than

示意图 Schematic illustration of xxx

%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%
% 结论 
%
%
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%

confirm the validity of our methods

we have presented an approach for ...

an interesting are for future research would be develop a formal model for augmenting ... feature vectors 

the relationship of ... , .... and ... also need to be better understood.



the results show the superior performance of ....

Extensive expriments have been designed and conducted to compared our proposed method to the state-of-art techniques such as ...


are the more desirable distance measures in terms of both retrieval effectiveness and
retrieval efficiency.

give slight better results than

perform slightly better than

performs surprisingly  well compared to the other methods

Experimental evaluation has shown that ... can outperform ...

the two approaches often yield approximately the same performance.

we believe that the results presented in this work can dramatically improve the computational efficiency of such algorithms.

substantially improves the quality of 

An important contribution of this work is


.... approach can yield lower computational complexity and better performance.

.. approaches are a promising solution to ..

The retrieval performance measure used in the
evaluation is the precision and recall pair.

as well as

empirically shows that .. can be excellent alternative to 

the results were similar but slightly worse.
 
it is demostrated how 


the ability to well approximate ...

we descibe the ....

the resulting ... is demostrated by applications to .... and ...

... have played an important role in ...

we do claim that ...

we provide examples to demostrate the algorithms and their potential for...

without loss of generality this can considered as ...

we have included several other popular .. algorithms of comparable simplicity for comparison, but it is not possible to provide an exhausive comparison with all available  .... algorithms.

.. at the cost of a significant increase in computational complexity.

is crucial 

measuring the dissimilarity between images and parts of images is of central importance for low-level computer vision

 is one of the key issues in CBIR

will be described and evaluated/developed 

we have compared and contrasted the ... to ..


this paper empirically compares 

table 1 compares the property of different measures 

ground truth is .. via

quantitative performance evaluations are 

for a wide variety of dissimilarity measures

the major contribution here is 

the results are interpreted in order to explain 

perceptual similarity of attribute

strengths and limitations

we report on the result of a systematic comparison of 

we propose a methodology for the quantitative comparison

color is a purely pointwise property of images, texture involves notionof spational extent: a single point has no texture


Corel Stock Photo Library /Brodatz Album

From each of iamges we extracted sets of ... random,non-overlapping blocks size 8** pixels

leave-one-out procedure 留一法

a host of variants of these algorithms

.... is a popular recent approach to ...

algorithms for this task are base on the idea that

... algorithms attempt to uncover these parameters in order to find 

in this paper, we discuss the motivation, background, and algorithms proposed for manifold learning

a host of variants of these algorithm are examined

%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%

You do not need to be a rocket scientist to understand this.


%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%




%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%

Dear Dr.XX,
I am a first year graduate student from the department of XX at XX University, 
and I am investigating XXX now. I found that your article titled XXX is closely related to my research; 
however, I cannot get it through the databases my university purchased. 
Could you send me the full text of that paper? Thanks in advance.
Good luck with you research.
 
二是作者太忙，不是很愿意发全文给你。此时可以再次发邮件联系，不过要注意语气，
例如说”I send an email to you asked for the full text of your paper titled XXX XX days ago 
but have not received your reply, I guess maybe you are too busy or you have not received the email. ” 
(说明：方法3主要为尚永丰上课所授)




%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%
